♪ ♪
We're here at the
grand Atlanta home
of Cynthia Slayton,
best-selling author
of such steamy novels
as The Sex Machine,
Wives and Lovers
and The Queen of Love.
Who would have thought that
the writer of these torrid tales
is really an
old-fashioned homebody?
Carolyn, so nice to see you.
Hi.
Oh, what beautiful orchids.
You certainly have
a green thumb.
Well, thank you.
My husband Phillip and I have
spent many a romantic evening
in this garden.
Your husband Phillip Slayton
is also your business manager.
Oh, yes, indeed.
Phillip gave up a brilliant
career as a stockbroker
to devote himself
full-time to me.
Not many men
would do that, Cynthia.
Well, Phillip is one of a kind.
We'd love to meet your Phillip.
Phillip, come on in.
Hello, darling.
You look lovely. Thank you.
It's so nice that
you could join us.
Welcome to our home. Thank you.
I'm sure there's one thing that
our audience is dying to know.
Just what's it like to be
married to the most glamorous
novelist of our time?
Endlessly exciting.
A woman of infinite variety.
Darling.
Now you know the
source of my love stories.
And so, it's true after all.
Art does imitate life.
I could be writing on
a notepad if you like.
Good idea.
You're making my job easy.
Carolyn, I have been
a fan of yours for years.
I'm just thrilled that you
wanted to interview me.
Well, the pleasure is mine.
Thank you, Evelyn.
Well, I think we're ready.
Cynthia.
Hello, Carolyn. It's
so nice to see you.
What a beautiful home you have.
Thank you. We've
been very happy here.
There's one more thing
our viewers, I know,
are dying to find out.
Just how does a
refined lady like yourself
know all about the things
you write about in your books?
Flaubert was once
asked that same question.
And he replied that an artist
must lead an ordinary life
in order to imagine
the extraordinary.
We've enjoyed our
visit with you, Cynthia.
You're ever bit as
charming and gracious
as your heroines. Thank you.
And now to our viewers.
Good night from the
home of Cynthia Slayton.
Until next time, this
is Carolyn Worzin.
Thank you so much, Carolyn.
No, thank you,
Cynthia. It was fabulous.
Bye-bye. Bye.
That little lizard.
What does she mean,
how do I write things?
How am I supposed
to answer that?
And you were no help.
"A woman of infinite variety."
What am I, assorted nuts?
If you say so, darling.
Can I get you anything?
I just want to be left alone.
This whole thing
has been a nightmare!
You should have seen
your sister's interview.
I hear Cynthia was
charming for almost an hour.
That's a record.
She asked me to
schedule the magazine
for a photo layout
this afternoon.
You think she's up to it?
We'll find out.
Hello, everyone.
Where's Cynthia?
Elizabeth, you have
no idea what it was like.
The woman is a Madame
Defarge of the first order.
First she was begging me
to do her shabby
little television show...
And it's a local
show, mind you...
And then she tried
to humiliate me.
I feel wretched.
Well, we'll just do the
photo layout some other time.
Oh, you're a dream.
Thank you, sweetheart.
What are you looking at?
I'm not dead, just distressed.
Oh, personally, I never
miss a bravura performance.
Joanna my pet,
why don't you find a man
who likes boring women
and then get married.
You're beginning to
wear on my nerves.
What doesn't, : Cynthia?
How can you treat her that way
after what she did for you?
So she took care of me
for a couple of months
after I had back surgery.
The surroundings aren't
exactly uncomfortable.
I noticed she stayed.
She gave up a
promising career for you.
She doesn't have what
it takes to be a model.
And I've always treated
her badly; she expects it.
Oh, dear, is Nefertiti
in here, Mrs. Slayton?
How the hell should I know?
Well, don't just stand
there, go look for her.
Phillip, did you
get my allergy pills
from the drugstore?
They're in the master
suite bathroom,
but it's not her prescription.
An allergy's an
allergy, for God's sake.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll be back in a minute.
What are you looking
so anxious about?
Oh, I'm sorry, ma'am, it's just
been sort of an awkward day.
I expect my personal secretaries
to be composed and
efficient at all times.
If there is any falling
apart to be done,
I will do it.
It's all right, Evelyn.
None of us could get
through the day without you.
Now what?
She's dead.
Hello, Miss March.
Hi. How are you?
Julie, I have been
looking all over for you.
You've got to get
a phone in your car.
That's the only
place I get any peace.
What's the rush?
The Elizabeth Lyle murder.
You haven't heard about it?
No.
Don't you have a
radio in your car either?
It is a great case.
Murder by mistake.
He was trying to kill his wife.
Cynthia Slayton no less.
Dave, I know Phillip Slayton.
Good.
That'll give you a head start.
You got the case.
I've already handled the
plea and the arraignment.
It's all in there.
But I can't prosecute him.
He's a friend of mine.
Hey, don't tell me.
Tell the boss.
He makes the assignments.
I will. Where is he?
He's gone.
Till Tuesday.
Where?
I don't know.
He doesn't have a
phone in his car either.
Look, don't get upset.
When he gets
back, just tell him,
He'll reassign it
to somebody else.
Bye.
Julie.
Hello, Phillip.
You're here in your
official capacity?
No, no.
I'm here as a friend.
You know I'm not a murderer.
Oh, Phillip, I-I can't
discuss the case.
I just came by to see
if you were all right.
All I did was pick up
the pills at that drugstore.
I had no idea there was
anything wrong with them. Please.
You shouldn't discuss this
without your lawyer's consent.
My lawyer.
He says it's transferred intent.
What with the big
insurance policy on Cynthia.
He wants me to plead
guilty to a reduced charge...
Manslaughter.
Who's your lawyer?
Malcolm Parks.
What I need is
a criminal lawyer.
Is there anybody
you'd recommend?
Julie, I just couldn't possibly.
But you could get a continuance.
But I'm due in Texas
to get that honorary degree
from Braddock University.
Then there's the Thruble case.
I didn't even know you went to
Braddock University. I-I didn't.
But they've been
after me for two years
to do this graduation speech,
and I got tired of saying no.
Well, it's a wonderful
honor, Ben, wonderful.
But Phillip Slayton is innocent.
I know it.
I appreciate how you
feel about your friend,
and I'm sure he must
be... He's got a lawyer!
A lawyer who's ready
to sell him out, Ben.
Damn!
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
I mean, wrong.
I'm not having my tonsils
out or my wisdom teeth pulled.
How about warts?
Look, all of my
electricity is out,
and my water isn't running!
Well, it runs a little,
but mostly it just hisses.
Well, why don't you call
an electrician or plumber?
I did just before
my phone went out.
Oh, that must be my cab.
Ben, what should I do?
I can't just stand by and let
him get convicted. Well, Julie,
you can still be
the DA on the case
till court convenes on Monday.
You can question witnesses
and you can investigate the case
and you know where
I am, you can call me
if I can be any
help and, and bye.
Thank you.
Bye! Bye.
Hey, Ben, can I stay here
until everything is fixed?
Thanks, pal.
Listen, if I could be
of any help, you know,
I've read all of Cynthia
Slayton's books.
Well... Let me put
it to you this way.
If they gave college
credit for Cynthia Slayton,
I'd be a PhD!
I wish this case were
a Cynthia Slayton book.
At least there'd
be a happy ending.
I bailed him out.
Then you're going
to stand by Phillip?
Well, my readers expect it.
Picture this.
Glamorous...
best-selling author arrives
at the filthiest police
station you've ever seen
to bail out the husband accused
of trying to murder her.
It's a fabulous scene.
Or it would have been if Phillip
hadn't messed up the big kiss.
Cynthia never misses
a photo opportunity.
She arrived with a
dozen reporters and...
flung herself at
me dramatically.
And you missed my
mouth completely.
Tomorrow the tabloids are
going to be running a picture
of Phillip kissing my earring.
Well, anyway, I'm glad
you're home, Phillip.
Thank you.
So am I.
So, you're here to help Phillip?
Yes, if I can.
Well, go ahead,
teach Phillip how
to impress a jury.
I think the best
way to help Phillip
is to find out who
tried to kill you.
Well, it wasn't Phillip.
Murder is an act
of passionate anger.
Look at him.
The best he can
muster is mild dismay.
Cynthia gets excited
now for both of us.
So you believe
Phillip is innocent,
even though he has a substantial
insurance policy on your life?
You mean a million dollars?
Should've been $20
million or $50 million.
Phillip thinks small.
Most people would consider
a million dollars motive.
I'm not most people.
I'll vouch for that.
Isn't Phillip your sole heir?
Yes, and I am his, although
what I would inherit from Phillip
probably wouldn't keep
me in fake fingernails.
Are you trying to convict him?
I'm just asking the questions
the D.A.'s going
to ask in court.
And I am getting tired
of answering them,
so why don't you go talk
to Evelyn and Joanna,
and I will change for lunch.
Phillip, you're coming with
me, so wear the blue suit.
Sweetheart, would you
mind going without me?
I'm expecting a
long-distance call.
If it's business.
Just a minute.
One more question.
Wasn't the deceased
your best friend?
Elizabeth?
I'll miss her.
'Course, she had
popcorn for brains,
but we all adored
her, didn't we, Philip?
She was a very nice woman.
Nice?
What an epitaph.
Who's Joanna?
My sister-in-law.
I believe she's
having a tennis lesson.
Good one.
Keep that racket up, now.
That's right.
Right to me. Good.
Nice and easy.
There you go.
Whoa! Enough, enough!
Hey!
All right, all right.
Ah, thanks.
Let's do it again.
See you Thursday. Okay.
Hello.
I'm Julie March.
Welcome to Oz...
You've met the witch?
You mean your sister, Cynthia?
Who else?
So...
Phillip tells me you're
a district attorney?
Yeah.
Are you prosecuting his case?
Oh, no, I'm just trying to
find out what happened.
Do you know anybody who
might want to kill Cynthia?
The line forms to the
right and extends to Alaska.
Why is that?
She humiliates people.
She digs for their secrets and
then exposes them in her books.
Oh, she's ruthless.
Has she ever written
about you?
No, thank you.
Of course.
I'm usually the, um...
loyal but boring
friend of the heroine.
And you resent that?
I don't take it personally.
She treats everyone badly.
Does that include Phillip?
The night Elizabeth died,
Phillip objected to her
taking Cynthia's pills,
and Cynthia
completely ignored him.
No, she treats
him with contempt.
It sounds like Cynthia's success
hasn't made her very happy.
You don't want to
cross her, Miss March.
You know,
I don't understand.
If Cynthia is so unpleasant,
why do you still live here?
She needs me.
All of her so-called friends
only love her success.
I knew her when she
was nobody, and, uh...
You love her.
She's my sister.
I suppose
I still love her.
I just wish I liked her.
Excuse me, I'm
gonna take a shower.
You've got to give me more time.
There's been a murder...
This place is a zoo.
Don't threaten me.
I'm doing my best.
Yes. That's ten for dinner.
The duck, the pilaf, and
the grilled vegetables.
Wonderful. Good-bye.
What can I do for you?
I just wanted to ask
you a few questions.
I'll have to clear that
with Mrs. Slayton first.
Oh, she went to lunch.
You sound a
little afraid of her.
I like my job, Miss March.
Is there anything else?
I am late for lunch. Yes, uh...
how do Mr. and Mrs.
Slayton get along?
That's not my place to say.
I will tell you this.
Phillip Slayton deserves better.
♪ ♪
Hello?
Hello, Ben?
Oh, Julie!
I just got in.
Yeah. This is great.
I'm being wined and
dined, real VIP treatment.
That's just wonderful, Ben.
You sound like you're calling
from the bottom of a barrel.
You didn't get one of
those car phones, did you?
No, I'm at a pay phone.
What's going on?
Oh, plenty.
Phillip told Cynthia he
was waiting for a phone call,
and then he snuck
out of the house
and he-he went to a motel.
That's where I am right now.
He just went inside.
Oh, Julie...
you-you'd better call
Tyler to do that kind of stuff.
You're not an investigator.
Julie?
Julie! Ben...
you're not going
to believe this.
The other woman
in Phillip's life...
you know who she is?
Cynthia's sister, Joanna.
If those books
Cynthia Slayton writes
are anything like her real
life, no wonder she's such a hit.
Hi, Julie. Heard from Ben?
Yes. Braddock University
is treating him like royalty.
What's that?
Oh, the latest scoop.
Listen to this.
"A distraught
"Cynthia Slayton sobs,
"I love my husband
beyond all reason.
Why should he want to kill me?"
His own wife thinks he did it.
No, she doesn't.
But it says right here.
Les, that is hardly
a reliable source.
I'll have you know
this paper has a
99% accuracy rate.
And that's in its
psychic predictions alone.
If the Informer
says it, it's true.
If you ever get jury duty,
I'll write you an excuse.
That's very kind
of you, Julie, but
I've never been one
to shirk my responsibilities.
Oh, would you like to
join me for dinner tonight?
Meat loaf at Templin's?
Oh, Les, thank you,
but I have an errand.
Ah, Miss March,
won't you come in?
If you're looking for Cynthia,
she's still at the salon
having everything waxed.
Yes, I know. I'm
here to see Phillip.
Bad news?
Julie! Hi.
We have to talk.
Just a minute... This
involves you, too.
I know that you
and Phillip spent the
afternoon at a motel.
Now, Phillip, please.
I don't like this any
more than you do,
believe me. Then why don't you
just forget what you
saw? Because one person
is already dead.
And Phillip is
accused of murder.
I think it's time for the truth.
You're right.
The truth is that Joanna
and I love each other.
I suppose that's the real
reason you stay here, too.
Look...
I know it's wrong.
I just wanted to be near him.
Phillip and I are
both Cynthia's victims.
That's what brought
us together at first.
Unfortunately, that
also gives you a motive
for getting rid of her.
Julie, I don't
have to kill Cynthia
to be free of her.
Joanna and I will simply leave.
Without telling Cynthia?
Without telling Cynthia what?
You botch my investments?
Even worse than that.
I'm in love with another woman.
How like you, Phillip...
Not only do you confess
to an affair you had
who knows how long ago,
but you manage to do it in
front of your friend and my sister.
We'll talk later.
No.
I'm not talking about
some past affair.
I love somebody now.
Cynthia...
Shut up, Joanna! This
doesn't concern you.
Yes, it does.
We love each other.
Joanna?
I'm sorry.
I'm not.
Get out, both of you.
Cynthia...
Get out of my house!
Phillip, at least now
we have a future.
Not quite.
You may have
just sunk your case.
Good morning, Julie.
Mm.
Hmm.
You look tired.
Uh! Vitamins.
Phillip Slayton's case
took a turn for the worse,
and I didn't get
any sleep last night.
You shouldn't be
staking out motels.
Ben called you?
Would you please let
me help you with this?
Oh, Tyler, thank you.
I could use the help.
Oh, excuse me.
Oh, come on in, Miss Morrell.
Thank you very much, Miss March.
When my office finishes
with those depositions,
we'll send them right over.
Thank you, Mr. Hudson.
Good morning.
Morning.
Hello. Hi.
I came by to apologize.
I've been rude to you
and everybody else.
I'm afraid living with Cynthia
has brought out my hostility.
Well, that's easy
to understand.
Please, sit down.
Thank you.
Now tell me why
you're really here.
I'm afraid you don't believe
in Phillip's innocence.
Because I found
out about your affair?
I was in love with Phillip
for years, and he knew it.
And he never even
so much as kissed me
until I made him realize
that what he felt for Cynthia
was loyalty, wasn't love.
You made him realize?
Phillip is a wonderful man.
He's decent, he's
caring, he's honorable.
I could not stand by and
watch him blame himself
for a failing marriage.
You mean, he
thought it was his fault?
Phillip is the kind of man
who feels responsible
for everything.
Do you believe in his innocence?
Yes.
Of course, I do.
That's what I needed to hear.
Thank you, Miss March.
You've been very, very kind.
Thank you, too.
Joanna...
when this is over,
what do you plan to do?
Make Phillip very happy.
Hello.
Is something wrong?
No.
No, I just thought we might chat
a little more freely away
from Cynthia's office.
Lord knows I could
use a change of scene.
Chat about what?
Well, the last time we talked,
I think you were on the phone
in Cynthia's office.
Yes, I remember.
I was calling the caterer.
That's what you said,
but I didn't believe you.
Nobody gets that
upset about duck.
All right, so I wasn't
calling the caterer.
Aren't I entitled
to a private life?
Even one that
might be upsetting?
Oh, yes, of course you are.
But your lie made
me a little curious,
so I did some checking,
and I found out
that in the past year,
you've made several phone calls
to a Mr. Richard Lee
Productions in Los Angeles.
And your bank statement shows
that you've been
depositing checks
from the same Richard Lee
into your personal
checking account.
What's going on?
I don't have to tell you.
No, you don't.
But when Phillip comes to trial,
both his attorney
and the prosecution
will have this information.
And Phillip's attorney
will be more than curious
about what it is you're
hiding from Cynthia
and whether or not
it's a motive for murder.
I didn't try to murder Cynthia!
Then you'd better tell
me what you're hiding.
I was selling Richard Lee copies
of Cynthia's first drafts.
That way, he could decide
in advance whether he
wanted the movie rights,
then he could
put in the bid first
before the rights
went to auction.
Richard has produced
two Cynthia Slayton novels
as television miniseries.
Let me get this straight.
You were stealing
Cynthia's manuscripts?
It's simpler than that.
Cynthia uses a computer, so
every time she would give me
a disk to edit, I would
just send it by phone
to Richard's modem
in Los Angeles.
But on the phone that day,
you sounded very upset.
I was.
Richard Lee was angry with me
because I hadn't sent
him any material lately.
Cynthia has stopped giving
me her computer disks.
When?
About two months ago.
She never gave me a reason,
but she just won't let
me near her computer.
Did she stop working?
No. No, in fact, for weeks,
she was locked in her office
pounding on her
computer day and night.
I wonder what she was writing.
So does Richard Lee.
I tried to sneak the
material out of her computer,
but she has a secret
access code I can't crack.
"To all who may read
"these letters, greeting.
That Benjamin Matlock"...
That's written in...
"Esq. has been awarded
the degree of Doctor of Law."
That part's printed.
And then the date and
the signature and all.
And I'm going to
put it on the wall
next to the speckled trout.
Oh, Ben, that's great.
Listen...
Uh, that's not
all. That's not all.
The Braddock University
Law Department
wants to name a chair after me.
A chair, yeah, a chair...
In philosophy of
law of all things.
Isn't that something?
Oh, that's fabulous.
And well deserved, too.
Congratulations.
Listen, Ben...
What-what's that you were saying
about Cynthia
Slayton's new book?
I was saying that she's
hiding it in her computer.
Now, this is just a hunch,
but I think Cynthia's
hidden material
has everything to
do with this case.
But I can't show
cause for a warrant,
because, I mean, a court
isn't going to accept hunches.
And I certainly can't break
and enter her computer.
No.
No, you can't.
But-but, hey, you know what?
What?
All right, the coast is clear.
I'll see you later. Good luck.
Thanks.
Lights.
All right.
Here we go.
What's wrong?
Don't worry.
I'll get it.
All right, let's try one more.
Jackpot.
Sounds like Cynthia's car.
She's at the front door.
Did she see you? Just missed me.
Good.
Where is it?
I didn't have time
to make a copy. Oh!
So, I sent it over the
modem to Ben's office.
It's waiting for us there.
Tyler, you're the best.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
I'm back.
Ben!
Oh, I didn't mean to scare you.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were
speaking tomorrow in Texas.
I canceled.
Why?
You know why they wanted to
give me that honorary degree?
They think you're
a great lawyer.
They think I'm a rich lawyer.
And that Benjamin
Matlock Chair of Law
they were going to endow?
I was going to endow.
They were going
to be the endowees.
So, the hell with them.
I left.
Endow my own chair.
I'm sorry. How have
things been going?
Take a look.
I was right about Phillip.
Did you tell him?
I sure did.
He fired his lawyer.
Oh.
Am I too late?
Mrs. Slayton, please tell
the court what happened
when Elizabeth Lyle
was exposed to your cat.
She began to sneeze.
She couldn't seem
to stop, so I suggested
that she take one of
my allergy capsules.
Phillip had just
brought a new bottle home.
What happened next?
She went upstairs.
A moment later,
there was a crash.
We all ran to the master bath
and found that Beth was dead.
Mrs. Slayton, those pills
your husband brought home
were prescribed for
you, weren't they? Yes.
I have chronic
allergies. Mm-hmm.
How-how often do you take them?
Twice a day.
Once in the morning
and one before bed.
So, if Elizabeth Lyle
hadn't taken the first capsule
from that new bottle,
you would have taken it
before you went to bed
that night, wouldn't you?
Yes.
And you would have
died in your sleep.
And in all likelihood, it would
have been ascribed
to natural causes.
Objection.
The woman died instantaneously
when she took the pill.
Mr. Hawkins said that
Mrs. Slayton would've
died in her sleep,
that's different.
Withdraw the question.
Mrs. Slayton, if
you were to die,
who are your beneficiaries?
My husband gets everything.
He'd be richer than
he ever dreamed.
There's a million-dollar
life insurance policy
and an estate worth
well over $20 million.
He and my loving sister
could live happily ever after.
Thank you.
No further questions.
Mr. Matlock.
Thank you.
Uh, Ms. Slayton...
you are one of the
most popular novelists
writing in America today.
In the last several
years, all of your books
have been way at the top of
the best seller lists, haven't they?
I've been very fortunate. Yeah.
And they've made a
lot of them into movies
and mini-series, haven't they?
Yes, they have.
But you haven't had a
new book in some time.
That's right.
A dry spell?
Well, there are
times when a writer
feels more
productive than others.
I'd say I was
replenishing myself.
Objection!
Your Honor, I fail
to see the relevancy
of Mrs. Slayton's
writing career.
Your Honor, the only thing
we know about this
woman is her writing career.
I gotta start somewhere.
Sit down, David! Mr. Matlock,
I'll tell Mr. Hawkins
when to sit.
Yes, sir. Overruled.
Proceed.
Thank you.
Uh, I-I heard that-that
about three months ago,
you started a new
novel. Yes, I did.
Well, when will we
see it published?
Well, you won't.
I abandoned the idea.
Why?
Well, sometimes an idea
works out and sometimes not.
It's that simple.
Oh.
Well, uh, would
you tell the court,
um, what it was about?
Well, it was about
a rather glamorous
and very successful woman.
Not unlike yourself.
I suppose.
And what happened?
Well, I only wrote
three chapters.
Ms. Slayton,
tell us, where do you get
the ideas for your novels?
Reality, imagination...
one would hope, a little talent.
Sometimes you get an idea
from a real person
and a real situation
and then enlarge on it?
I couldn't have
put it better myself.
Thank you.
Uh, I have, uh...
a little collection of,
uh, some of your reviews.
I'm not what you'd call
the darling of the critics.
No, no, you're not.
But some of them
like your stories.
Now, here, for instance,
from the New York Journal.
"Mrs. Slayton's story
is a finely crafted work."
So, you, you do a lot
of work on the story.
You spend a lot of time
on the story.
The story's
everything. Your Honor!
We have followed Mr. Matlock
down this tortured path
and seem to be back
where we started.
Which, as far as I
can tell, is nowhere!
Your Honor, Mr. Hawkins
is on his feet again.
Mr. Matlock... If he wants
to stretch, that's okay,
but he doesn't have
to talk while he does it.
I'm warning you.
Your Honor, this will only take
a few more minutes
if I might continue.
You're trying my
patience, too, Mr. Matlock,
but proceed.
Thank you, thank you.
Uh, when you write a novel,
do you start with an outline?
Oh, yes.
Sometimes the outline
is 60, 70 pages long.
I can't start a novel
until I know where
it's going to wind up.
Oh... yeah, right.
Do you ever get stuck?
All the time.
Well, what do you do
when you get stuck?
I spend a lot of time
looking out windows
and staring at walls.
Do you ever go, uh,
talk to anybody about it?
Sometimes. Uh-huh.
Have you ever been to see a
woman named Katharine Scott
to talk to her about it?
Yes, I have.
In fact, uh, the last time
you went to talk
to Katharine Scott,
was the day you decided
to abandon the book.
Wasn't it?
I believe so, yes.
Uh, Ms. Scott is
in the courtroom,
and she is prepared to testify
that the heroine in your book...
Glamorous, successful,
not unlike yourself...
Believed her husband
was having an affair
with her best friend.
Is that right?
It's been a while since
I worked on the story.
Well, now, I can call Ms. Scott
to the stand.
Yes, that's what it was about.
And so, your heroine
decided to, uh, take revenge
on her husband
and her best friend.
Yes.
Well, that sounds
like a good story.
Why'd you stop?
As I said, the story
didn't work for me.
Or...
maybe it worked too well.
Like your heroine, you believed
your husband...
was having an affair
with your best friend,
Elizabeth Lyle.
And that's why you
stopped writing the book.
Because you planned
to take revenge in real life.
I don't have to listen to
these unfounded accusations.
Okay.
Let's substantiate them.
Now, all along we've believed
those poisoned capsules
were meant for you.
And that somehow,
Elizabeth got one
of them by mistake.
But that's not really
what happened, is it?
Who let the cat into the room
to trigger Elizabeth's
allergic reaction?
I didn't know the cat was there.
I believe you knew
the cat was there; I believe
you brought the cat there.
That is not true.
Are these the, uh...
capsules...
your husband picked up for you?
Yes.
And when she started
having her allergic
reaction, sneezing,
you told her to take one of
these capsules, didn't you?
Yes, but that is
perfectly logical.
I didn't know the
capsules were poisoned.
Who's your allergist?
Dr. Cooper. Dr. Cooper.
And who...
Who is Dr. Moss?
I don't know.
I have a prescription here
in your name from Dr. Moss.
Now, you have to
listen very carefully
because this is
very complicated.
I suppose that's
the way writers think.
These are the capsules
that your husband
picked up from Dr. Cooper.
This is the prescription
that she picked up herself
from Dr. Moss
just a day before
Elizabeth died.
You had to poison
all the capsules
in this bottle to be sure
that whichever
capsule Elizabeth got,
it would do her in.
But you needed
medication yourself.
So, she went to a doctor
she had never been to before
and had the prescription
filled by a druggist
she didn't know.
That doesn't prove anything.
Yes, it does.
It proves
that you knew these
capsules were poisoned
and the only reason
you could've known
they were poisoned
is because you
poisoned them yourself.
You let the cat in
to trigger her
allergic reaction.
And when Elizabeth
started to sneeze,
you told her to take
one of these capsules,
knowing what the
consequence would be.
Oh, it was perfect.
It was perfect.
It was like a page out
of one of your books.
Plotted... great.
But you killed the wrong person.
Your husband
wasn't having an affair
with Elizabeth Lyle.
He was having an affair
with your very own sister.
Isn't it a shame?
You killed the wrong person.
Tsk.
Nothing further.
Uh, at this time, Your Honor,
the state would like to dismiss
all charges against
the defendant.
Good idea.
Case dismissed.
Court is adjourned.
David, that was
just a little devilment.
I think you look nice
when you stand up.
Thank-thank you.
Thank-thank you both very much.
"Jessica dropped her robe
"and stood naked
in front of the mirror.
"She contemplated her
nude body for a long time.
"She was still
firm, still desirable.
"Many men had told her so.
"Then how could this
be happening to her?"
Could, could I say something?
Hush!
Um, I'm sorry I wasn't here,
but this case couldn't have
been handled any better.
Thank you. Are you
gonna let her read?
And if you ever decide to
change sides, let me know.
Are you through?
Well... Then sit down.
Uh, hmph!
Go on.
Excuse me.
"She could imagine
Donald cheating on her,
"though the thought was
like a knife in her flesh.
"But it had to be true.
"The two of them laughing at her
"as they shared each
other's bodies in secret.
"The smutty images
exploded in Jessica's mind.
"Her taut flesh quivered
"as she threw her cut crystal
tumbler against the wall,
"the brandy dribbled
down the silk wall covering...
like tears."
www.tvsubtitles.net